Dr Tristan Friedrich KLEINSCHMIDT

NATIONALITY Australian

30th of December 1983 DATE OF BIRTH

CONTACT 15 Sleeper Street Phone: +1 (617) 372-4196

INFORMATION Apt. #407 Email: kleinschmidt_tf@yahoo.com.au

Boston, MA, USA 02210 LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/tristan-

kleinschmidt-97947515

PROFESSIONAL PHILOSOPHY

• Problem solving: use the right tool for the business problem

• Communication: simplify complexity, make it actionable

• Enablement: user empowerment elevates value from data science insights and tools

• Team management: active communities brings out the best in people, accelerates innovation

• Sustainability: decisions made now must have sustainable impact for our planet

SUMMARY

DATA SCIENCE SKILL • Discrete-event simulation (DES): 12yrs experience delivering DES for capital and operational decisions, across mining & minerals, manufacturing, and financial institutions

> • Mathematical optimization: manufacturing production scheduling & commodity pricing using mixed integer programming

Machine learning (ML): arrival prediction of bulk carriers using gradient-boosted machines

DATA SCIENCE SOFTWARE SKILLS • Languages: Python, Java, C/C++

• Simulation: AnyLogic, ARENA, Python (SimPy)

• Optimization: Python (PuLP, pyomo), AIMMS, Gurobi

• Machine Learning: Python, sci-kit learn

• General: Git, SVN, AWS, Matlab, R, Tableau, PowerBI, SQL, Docker

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Consultant and Senior Data Scientist

February 2019 - Current

BCG Gamma, The Boston Consulting Group, Boston/Singapore/Sydney

- Gamma North America Simulation Co-Lead, responsible for building regional DES capability, project pipeline, and training and mentoring of junior simulation practitioners
- Responsible for simulation & optimization project delivery, marketing BCG proprietary data science capabilities and methodologies
- Discrete-event simulation (DES) of credit operations in India to optimize daily, weekly & monthly rosters and campaign plans
- Development of a scenario planning tool using BCG proprietary methodologies for Covid-19 testing to inform Asia-Pacific air transport recovery during early phases of global pandemic
- DES of beneficiation plant: identified co-commitments to deliver volume targets for a \$70m investment
- ML prediction of bulk carrier arrival time at load port: 5-15% precision increase over existing model
- Medium-term market price discovery for commodity market using mixed integer programming: potential \$90m profit increase
- Integrated sales and operations planning optimization for pulp and paper mills, palm oil refineries: identified up to 10% margin improvement

Principal Consultant

January 2012 – January 2019

The Simulation Group, Brisbane/Perth, Australia

- Simulation consulting projects regional team lead; responsible for project excellence, team management, recruiting & training, supporting business development activities
- Copper concentrator design verification: defined maintenance and 3rd-party logistics requirements to achieve production targets for multiple \$2b+ greenfield projects
- Volume risk assessment of iron ore and coal capital projects: identified more robust infrastructure and product strategies worth additional \$400m+ NPV
- · Capital expansion planning and operational improvements across iron ore, coal, copper and aluminium mining and processing, as well as public rail networks and brick making facilities

Project Officer

January 2010 – *January* 2012

Airports of the Future Project, Queensland University of Technology, Brisbane, Australia

- Managed collaboration of 30+ global research partners investigating the future of air travel
- Secured \$900k to establish Integrated Command & Control Facility for Large-Scale Critical Infrastructure Management
- Team awarded 2011 Engineers Australia QLD Division Engineering Excellence Award for R&D
- Published 3 peer-reviewed journal articles & 5 international conference papers, including research focus on airport passenger simulation using agent-based modelling

EDUCATION

Doctor of Philosophy (Elec Eng)

2006 - 2010

Queensland University of Technology, Brisbane, Australia

- Dissertation Title: "Robust Speech Recognition using Speech Enhancement"
- Principal Supervisor: Professor Sridha Sridharan
- Associate Supervisor: Dr Michael Mason
- Key Research Areas: Automotive Speech Recognition and Speech Enhancement

Graduate Certificate in Research Commercialisation

March 2008 - June 2008

Queensland University of Technology, Brisbane, Australia

Master of Engineering Science (Computer & Communications)

February 2005 - January 2006

Queensland University of Technology, Brisbane, Australia

Bachelor of Engineering (Electrical & Computer) with First Class Honours February 2002 – July 2005

Queensland University of Technology, Brisbane, Australia Awarded the QUT University Medal, 2006.

HOBBIES & COMMUNITY

- parkrun volunteer, St Lucia (QLD), Bishan (Singapore), & Danehy Park (Boston) parkruns, 2018 2022.
- Running
- Travel
- Photography

PROFESSIONAL REFEREES

Referees available on request